VIPUL SUREKA

7892913715 vipulsureka246@gmail.com

I'm a B.Tech. graduate with close to 4 yrs of experience as a Data Analyst. I'm currently a Consultant at Deloitte and I like working with numbers. I love communicating and have got story-telling capabilities. I'm exploring the Data Field and open to learning new technologies and have worked with world's largest FMCG companies and looking forward to joining an organisation where I could help the Company grow as well as develop my own skills as a Data enthusiast.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Consultant (current)/ Data Analyst 2

Deloitte

9/2020-Present

Tenure: (9/2023 - Till Date) Client Industry: FMCG

- Implemented client feedback and change requests, enhancing existing reports with 2 sources (Excel and SQL), which showed the freshness overview and details at Factory, DC, CD and On shelf.
- Significantly contributing to the success of our most revenue-generating client in India, generating approximately 1 Million Dollars in revenue for the company.

Tenure: (7/2023 - 9/2023)

- Created a Request for Proposal for a client from Manufacturing field and led the PowerBI training initiatives which included training of 80 to 100 members per month.
- Recognized the potential of our existing CSR report and proposed the idea to my managers to pitch it to the client, which led to the exploration of potential integration of Looker and Looker Studio and was accepted by the one the largest tech giants of the world.

Tenure: (7/2022 - 7/2023) Client Industry: FMCG

- Leading the data visualization team and redesigning the old dashboards in PowerBI, which incorporated building a dataset which gave live data to users, usage of Rest API for customized complex queries and used incremental refresh on dataset which reduced the dataset refresh time from 3 hours to 25 minutes.
- Redesigned the architecture from ADF->Databricks ->PowerBI->Webapps to ADF->Databricks ->AAS ->Webapps, which reduced the data extraction time from 30-40 minutes to 5 minutes.

Tenure: (01/2022 - 06/2022) Client Industry: FMCG

• Contributed to Bug Fixes and Change requests for the previous Indonesia Project (Apr-Jul '21), which improved the performance as per the business, which included standardization of fonts and colors, designing as per the Zeplin wireframe, the calculations and page change should load within 15 seconds, etc.

Tenure: (07/2021 - 12/2021) Client Industry: FMCG

- Involved in developing pipelines using Azure Data Factory and using data bricks notebooks and stored procedure, where this infra change optimized the run times of daily data loads by 34%.
- Redesigned the architecture from ADLS -> Synapse Analytics (SQL DW) -> Azure Analysis Service -> Power BI to ADLS ->
 Azure Databricks -> ADLS -> Power BI which brought the infra cost down by 40% and saved more than 300000 Euros per year.

Tenure: 4 Months (04/2021 - 07/2021) Client Industry: FMCG

- Developed 15+ dashboards using Power BI and Databricks, providing crucial insights into Primary & Secondary Sales and Market Performance.
- Contributed to Bug Fixes, change requests, and implemented DAX measures to create KPIs, improving data visualization accuracy for the client's 3rd largest market across the world.

Tenure: 3 Months (01/2021 - 03/2021) Client Industry: FMCG

• Developed 10+ dashboards that involved migration of BI tools – Tableau to Microsoft Power BI.

EDUCATION

Manipal, Karnataka

Manipal Institute of Technology

07/2016 - 06/2020

• B.Tech in Mechanical Engineering – 8.32 CGPA

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

- Web Scraping (from an Ecommerce site)
- Olympics Dataset Analysis
- EDA on IPL Dataset.
- Loan Approval Prediction System.
- Autonomous Vehicle System.

(Worked as Electronics Engineer) Rugved Systems- http://www.rugved.co.in 8th position in IGVC Challenge at Oakland University, Michigan, USA

ONLINE PRESENCE

- LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/vipulsureka/
- GitHub https://github.com/Vipul-Sureka
- Huggingface https://huggingface.co/VipulS
- Kaggle https://www.kaggle.com/vipulsureka
- Hackerrank https://www.hackerrank.com/Vipul_Sureka?hr_r=1

SKILLS

Advanced SQL, MS Excel, PowerBI, Azure Data Factory, Azure Databricks, Python (Basics), Statistics, Numpy & Pandas (Basics), Machine Learning (Basics), Leadership Experience.